Fear the monster within.
First Moon is a horror, thriller film directed by Peter McLeod.
A young waitress is abducted by a religious cult, who are hell-bent on curing her from
a sexually transmitted werewolf virus - or killing her in the process.
Will she escape before the first full moon?
Jessica, played by Lauren Esposito.
Thomas, played by Julian Curtis.
Elyse, played by Shannon Ryan.
Father Torquemada, played by Soren Jensen.
Matt, played by Mitchell Slater.
Monique, played by Yasmin Langlois.
Blue Moon is a 2025 American biographical comedy-drama film directed by Richard Linklater and written by
Robert Kaplow, reportedly inspired by the letters of Elizabeth Weiland to Lorenz Hart.
The film stars Ethan Hawke, Margaret Qualley, Bobby Cannavale and Andrew Scott.
Its plot follows Hart as he reflects on himself on the opening night of
Oklahoma!, a new musical by his former colleague Richard Rodgers.
Blue Moon had its world premiere at the main competition of the 75th Berlin International Film Festival on
February 18, 2025, where it won the Silver Bear for Best Supporting Performance for Scott.
At the 83rd Golden Globe Awards, it was nominated for Best Motion
Picture – Musical or Comedy and Best Actor for Hawke.
At the 98th Academy Awards, Kaplow was nominated for Best
Original Screenplay and Hawke for Best Actor.
It was theatrically released in the United States by Sony Pictures Classics on
October 17, 2025, and received positive reviews from critics.
The tone is dark and intense.